{
  "V201234": {
    "title": "PRE: GOVERNMENT RUN BY A FEW BIG INTERESTS OR FOR BENEFIT OF ALL",
    "question": "Would you say the government is pretty much run by a few big interests looking out for themselves or that it is run for the benefit of all the people?",
    "positive_answer": "Govt. is run for the benefit of all people.",
    "all_answers": [
      "Run by a few big interests",
      "For the benefit of all the people"
    ]
  },
  "V201235": {
    "title": "PRE: DOES GOVERNMENT WASTE MUCH TAX MONEY",
    "question": "Do you think that people in government waste a lot of the money we pay in taxes, waste some of it, or don’t waste very much of it?",
    "positive_answer": "Govt. doesn't waste much tax money.",
    "all_answers": [
      "Waste a lot",
      "Waste some",
      "Don’t waste very much"
    ]
  },
  "V201236": {
    "title": "PRE: HOW MANY IN GOVERNMENT ARE CORRUPT",
    "question": "How many of the people running the government are corrupt?",
    "positive_answer": "None running govt are corrupt",
    "all_answers": [
      "All",
      "Most",
      "About half",
      "A few",
      "None"
    ]
  },
  "V201237": {
    "title": "PRE: HOW OFTEN CAN PEOPLE BE TRUSTED",
    "question": "Generally speaking, how often can you trust other people?",
    "positive_answer": "People can never be trusted.",
    "all_answers": [
      "Always",
      "Most of the time",
      "About half the time",
      "Some of the time",
      "Never"
    ]
  },
  "V201238": {
    "title": "PRE: ELECTIONS MAKE GOVERNMENT PAY ATTENTION",
    "question": "How much do you feel that having elections makes the government pay attention to what the people think?",
    "positive_answer": "elections don't make govt pay attention,",
    "all_answers": [
      "A good deal",
      "Some",
      "Not much"
    ]
  },
  "V201246": {
    "title": "PRE: 7PT SCALE SPENDING & SERVICES: SELFPLACEMENT",
    "question": "Some people think the government should provide fewer services even in areas such as health and education in order to reduce spending. Suppose these people are at one end of a scale, at point 1. Other people feel it is important for the government to provide many more services even if it means an increase in spending. Suppose these people are at the other end, at point 7. Where would you place yourself on this scale, or haven’t you thought much about this?",
    "positive_answer": "govt provide many more services,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Government should provide many fewer services",
      "",
      "",
      "",
      "",
      "",
      "Government should provide many more services"
    ]
  },
  "V201249": {
    "title": "PRE: 7PT SCALE DEFENSE SPENDING: SELF-PLACEMENT",
    "question": "Some people believe that we should spend much less money for defense. Suppose these people are at one end of a scale, at point 1. Others feel that defense spending should be greatly increased. Suppose these people are at the other end, at point 7. Where would you place yourself on this scale, or haven’t you thought much about this?",
    "positive_answer": "more defense spending,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Greatly decrease defense spending",
      "",
      "",
      "",
      "",
      "",
      "Greatly increase defense spending"
    ]
  },
  "V201252": {
    "title": "PRE: 7PT SCALE GOV-PRIVATE MEDICAL INSURANCE SCALE: SELF-PLACEMENT",
    "question": "There is much concern about the rapid rise in medical and hospital costs. Some people feel there should be a government insurance plan which would cover all medical and hospital expenses for everyone. Suppose these people are at one end of a scale, at point 1. Others feel that all medical expenses should be paid by individuals through private insurance plans like Blue Cross or other company paid plans. Suppose these people are at the other end, at point 7.",
    "positive_answer": "private healthcare,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Government insurance plan",
      "",
      "",
      "",
      "",
      "",
      "Private insurance plan"
    ]
  },
  "V201255": {
    "title": "PRE: 7PT SCALE GUARANTEED JOB-INCOME SCALE: SELF-PLACEMENT",
    "question": "Some people feel the government in Washington should see to it that every person has a job and a good standard of living. Suppose these people are at one end of a scale, at point 1. Others think the government should just let each person get ahead on their own. Suppose these people are at the other end, at point 7.",
    "positive_answer": "govt shouldn't provide guaranteed jobs & ubi,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Government should see to jobs and standard of living",
      "",
      "",
      "",
      "",
      "",
      "Government should let each person get ahead on own"
    ]
  },
  "V201258": {
    "title": "PRE: 7PT SCALE GOV ASSISTANCE TO BLACKS SCALE: SELF-PLACEMENT",
    "question": "Some people feel that the government in Washington should make every effort to improve the social and economic position of blacks. Suppose these people are at one end of a scale, at point 1. Others feel that the government should not make any special effort to help blacks because they should help themselves. Suppose these people are at the other end, at point 7.",
    "positive_answer": "govt shouldnt help black people,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Government should help blacks",
      "",
      "",
      "",
      "",
      "",
      "Blacks should help themselves"
    ]
  },
  "V201262": {
    "title": "PRE: 7PT SCALE ENVIRONMENT-BUSINESS TRADEOFF: SELF-PLACEMENT",
    "question": "Some people think we need much tougher government regulations on business in order to protect the environment. Suppose these people are at one end of a scale, at point 1. Others think that current regulations to protect the environment are already too much of a burden on business. Suppose these people are at the other end, at point 7.",
    "positive_answer": "govt shouldn't protect environment,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Tougher regulations on business needed to protect environment",
      "",
      "",
      "",
      "",
      "",
      "Regulations to protect environment already too much a burden on business"
    ]
  },
  "V201302x": {
    "title": "PRE: FEDERAL BUDGET SPENDING: SOCIAL SECURITY",
    "question": "Should federal spending on Social Security be increased, decreased, or kept the same?",
    "positive_answer": "decrease social security spending,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Increased a lot",
      "Increased a little",
      "Kept the same",
      "Decreased a little",
      "Decreased a lot"
    ]
  },
  "V201305x": {
    "title": "PRE: SUMMARY: FEDERAL BUDGET SPENDING: PUBLIC SCHOOLS",
    "question": "Should federal spending on public schools be increased, decreased, or kept the same?",
    "positive_answer": "decrease public school spending,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Increased a lot",
      "Increased a little",
      "Kept the same",
      "Decreased a little",
      "Decreasaed a lot"
    ]
  },
  "V201308x": {
    "title": "PRE: SUMMARY: FEDERAL BUDGET SPENDING: TIGHTENING BORDER SECURITY",
    "question": "Should federal spending on tightening border security to prevent illegal immigration be increased, decreased, or kept the same?",
    "positive_answer": "decrease border security spending,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Increased a lot",
      "Increased a little",
      "Kept the same",
      "Decreased a little",
      "Decreasaed a lot"
    ]
  },
  "V201311x": {
    "title": "PRE: SUMMARY: FEDERAL BUDGET SPENDING: DEALING WITH CRIME",
    "question": "Should federal spending on dealing with crime be increased, decreased, or kept the same?",
    "positive_answer": "decrease crime prevention spending,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Increased a lot",
      "Increased a little",
      "Kept the same",
      "Decreased a little",
      "Decreasaed a lot"
    ]
  },
  "V201314x": {
    "title": "PRE: SUMMARY: FEDERAL BUDGET SPENDING: WELFARE PROGRAMS",
    "question": "Should federal spending on welfare programs be increased, decreased, or kept the same?",
    "positive_answer": "decrease welfare spending,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Increased a lot",
      "Increased a little",
      "Kept the same",
      "Decreased a little",
      "Decreasaed a lot"
    ]
  },
  "V201317x": {
    "title": "PRE: SUMMARY: FEDERAL BUDGET SPENDING: BUILDING AND REPAIRING HIGHWAYS",
    "question": "Should federal spending on building and repairing highways be increased, decreased, or kept the same?",
    "positive_answer": "decrease highway spending,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Increased a lot",
      "Increased a little",
      "Kept the same",
      "Decreased a little",
      "Decreasaed a lot"
    ]
  },
  "V201320x": {
    "title": "PRE: SUMMARY: FEDERAL BUDGET SPENDING: AID TO THE POOR",
    "question": "Should federal spending on aid to the poor be increased, decreased, or kept the same?",
    "positive_answer": "decrease poor aid spending,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Increased a lot",
      "Increased a little",
      "Kept the same",
      "Decreased a little",
      "Decreasaed a lot"
    ]
  },
  "V201323x": {
    "title": "PRE: SUMMARY: FEDERAL BUDGET SPENDING: PROTECTING THE ENVIRONMENT",
    "question": "Should federal spending on protecting the environment be increased, decreased, or kept the same?",
    "positive_answer": "decrease environment spending,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Increased a lot",
      "Increased a little",
      "Kept the same",
      "Decreased a little",
      "Decreasaed a lot"
    ]
  },
  "V201336": {
    "title": "RE: STD ABORTION: SELF-PLACEMENT",
    "question": "There has been some discussion about abortion during recent years. Which one of the opinions on this page best agrees with your view?",
    "positive_answer": "abortion always allowed,",
    "all_answers": [
      "By law, abortion should never be permitted",
      "The law should permit abortion only in case of rape, incest, or when the woman’s life is in danger",
      "The law should permit abortion other than for rape/incest/danger to woman but only after need clearly established",
      "By law, a woman should always be able to obtain an abortion as a matter of personal choice"
    ]
  },
  "V201345x": {
    "title": "PRE: SUMMARY: R FAVOR/OPPOSE DEATH PENALTY",
    "question": "Do you favor or oppose the death penalty for persons convicted of murder?",
    "positive_answer": "no death penalty,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Favor strongly",
      "Favor not strongly",
      "Oppose not strongly",
      "Oppose strongly"
    ]
  },
  "V201349x": {
    "title": "PRE: SUMMARY: COUNTRY WOULD BE BETTER OFF IF WE JUST STAYED HOME",
    "question": "‘This country would be better off if we just stayed home and did not concern ourselves with problems in other parts of the world.’",
    "positive_answer": "us should not stay home,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Agree strongly",
      "Agree somewhat",
      "Disagree somewhat",
      "Disagree strongly"
    ]
  },
  "V201350": {
    "title": "PRE: FORCE TO SOLVE INTERNATIONAL PROBLEMS",
    "question": "How willing should the United States be to use military force to solve international problems?",
    "positive_answer": "us shouldnt use force internationally,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Extremely willing",
      "Very willing",
      "Moderately willing",
      "A little willing",
      "Not at all willing"
    ]
  },
  "V201356x": {
    "title": "PRE: SUMMARY: FAVOR/OPPOSE VOTE BY MAIL",
    "question": "Do you favor, oppose, or neither favor nor oppose conducting all elections by mail, instead of people voting in-person?",
    "positive_answer": "vote in person,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Favor a great deal",
      "Favor moderately",
      "Favor a little",
      "Neither favor nor oppose",
      "Oppose a little",
      "Oppose moderately",
      "Oppose a great deal"
    ]
  },
  "V201359x": {
    "title": "PRE: SUMMARY: FAVOR/OPPOSE REQUIRING ID WHEN VOTING",
    "question": "Do you favor, oppose, or neither favor nor oppose requiring all people to show a government issued photo ID when they vote?",
    "positive_answer": "no voter id laws,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Favor a great deal",
      "Favor moderately",
      "Favor a little",
      "Neither favor nor oppose",
      "Oppose a little",
      "Oppose moderately",
      "Oppose a great deal"
    ]
  },
  "V201362x": {
    "title": "PRE: SUMMARY: FAVOR/OPPOSE ALLOWING FELONS TO VOTE",
    "question": "Do you favor, oppose, or neither favor nor oppose allowing convicted felons to vote once they complete their sentence?",
    "positive_answer": "ex felons should not vote,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Favor a great deal",
      "Favor moderately",
      "Favor a little",
      "Neither favor nor oppose",
      "Oppose a little",
      "Oppose moderately",
      "Oppose a great deal"
    ]
  },
  "V201366": {
    "title": "PRE: HOW IMPORTANT THAT NEWS ORGANIZATIONS FREE TO CRITICIZE",
    "question": "For the next few items, we would like to know how important you think each one is to the United States maintaining a strong democracy. First, how important is it that news organizations are free to criticize political leaders?",
    "positive_answer": "important that news can criticize politicians,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Not important at all",
      "A little important",
      "Moderately important",
      "Very important",
      "Extremely important"
    ]
  },
  "V201367": {
    "title": "PRE: HOW IMPORTANT BRANCHES OF GOVERNMENT KEEP ONE ANOTHER FROM TOO MUCH POWER",
    "question": "How important is it that the executive, legislative, and judicial branches of government keep one another from having too much power?",
    "positive_answer": "checks and balances important,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Not important at all",
      "A little important",
      "Moderately important",
      "Very important",
      "Extremely important"
    ]
  },
  "V201368": {
    "title": "PRE: HOW IMPORTANT ELECTED OFFICIALS FACE SERIOUS CONSEQUENCES FOR MISCONDUCT",
    "question": "How important is it that elected officials face serious consequences if they engage in misconduct?",
    "positive_answer": "important elected officials face consequences for misconduct,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Not important at all",
      "A little important",
      "Moderately important",
      "Very important",
      "Extremely important"
    ]
  },
  "V201369": {
    "title": "PRE: HOW IMPORTANT THAT PEOPLE AGREE ON BASIC FACTS",
    "question": "How important is it that people agree on basic facts even if they disagree politically?",
    "positive_answer": "important people agree on basic facts,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Not important at all",
      "A little important",
      "Moderately important",
      "Very important",
      "Extremely important"
    ]
  },
  "V201372x": {
    "title": "PRE: SUMMARY: HELPFUL/HARMFUL IF PRES DIDN’T HAVE TO WORRY ABOUT CONGRESS/COURTS",
    "question": "Would it be helpful, harmful, or neither helpful nor harmful if U.S. presidents could work on the country’s problems without paying attention to what Congress and the courts say?",
    "positive_answer": "bad if us president could bypass courts/congress,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Extremely helpful",
      "Moderately helpful",
      "A little helpful",
      "Neither helpful nor harmful",
      "A little harmful",
      "Moderately harmful",
      "Extremely harmful"
    ]
  },
  "V201375x": {
    "title": "PRE: SUMMARY: FAVOR OR OPPOSE RESTRICTING JOURNALIST ACCESS",
    "question": "Do you favor, oppose, or neither favor nor oppose elected officials restricting journalists’ access to information about government decision-making?",
    "positive_answer": "do not restrict journalist access to govt info,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Favor a great deal",
      "Favor moderately",
      "Favor a little",
      "Neither favor nor oppose",
      "Oppose a little",
      "Oppose moderately",
      "Oppose a great deal"
    ]
  },
  "V201376": {
    "title": "PRE: HOW CONCERNED GOVERNMENT MIGHT UNDERMINE MEDIA",
    "question": "How concerned are you that some people in the government today might want to undermine the news media’s ability to serve as a check on governmental power?",
    "positive_answer": "concerned govt want to undermine media,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Not at all concerned",
      "A little concerned",
      "Moderately concerned",
      "Very concerned",
      "Extremely concerned"
    ]
  },
  "V201377": {
    "title": "PRE: HOW MUCH TRUST IN NEWS MEDIA",
    "question": "In general, how much trust and confidence do you have in the news media when it comes to reporting the news fully, accurately, and fairly?",
    "positive_answer": "confident in news media,",
    "all_answers": [
      "None",
      "A little",
      "A moderate amount",
      "A lot",
      "A great deal"
    ]
  },
  "V201378": {
    "title": "PRE: APPROPRIATE/INAPPROPRIATE PRES ASK FOREIGN COUNTRIES TO INVESTIGATE RIVALS",
    "question": "In general, how appropriate or inappropriate is it for the president of the United States to ask leaders of foreign countries to investigate political rivals?",
    "positive_answer": "pres shouldnt ask foreign countries to investigate rivals,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Very appropriate",
      "Somewhat appropriate",
      "Neither appropriate nor inappropriate",
      "Somewhat inappropriate",
      "Very inappropriate"
    ]
  },
  "V201379": {
    "title": "PRE: PREFER GOVERNMENT OFFICIAL WHO COMPROMISES OR STICKS TO PRINCIPLES",
    "question": "Would you prefer a government official who compromises to get things done, or who sticks to their principles no matter what?",
    "positive_answer": "stick to principles and not compromise,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Compromises to get things done",
      "Sticks to their principles no matter what"
    ]
  },
  "V201386x": {
    "title": "PRE: SUMMARY: FAVOR OR OPPOSE HOUSE IMPEACHMENT DECISION",
    "question": "Do you favor, oppose, or neither favor nor oppose the U.S. House of Representatives’ decision in December of last year to impeach President Trump?",
    "positive_answer": "against trump impeachment house,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Favor a great deal",
      "Favor moderately",
      "Favor a little",
      "Neither favor nor oppose",
      "Oppose a little",
      "Oppose moderately",
      "Oppose a great deal"
    ]
  },
  "V201389x": {
    "title": "PRE: SUMMARY: FAVOR OR OPPOSE SENATE ACQUITTAL DECISION",
    "question": "Do you favor, oppose, or neither favor nor oppose the U.S. Senate’s decision in February to acquit President Trump of the impeachment charges and thus let him remain in office?",
    "positive_answer": "support trump impeachment senate,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Favor a great deal",
      "Favor moderately",
      "Favor a little",
      "Neither favor nor oppose",
      "Oppose a little",
      "Oppose moderately",
      "Oppose a great deal"
    ]
  },
  "V201392x": {
    "title": "PRE: SUMMARY: FEDERAL GOVERNMENT RESPONSE TO COVID-19",
    "question": "Do you think the federal government’s response to the COVID-19 outbreak earlier this year was too quick, too slow, or aboutright?",
    "positive_answer": "covid response too slow,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Much too quick",
      "Somewhat too quick",
      "About right",
      "Somewhat too slow",
      "Much too slow"
    ]
  },
  "V201405x": {
    "title": "PRE: SUMMARY: REQUIRE EMPLOYERS TO OFFER PAID LEAVE TO PARENTS OF NEW CHILDREN",
    "question": "Do you favor, oppose, or neither favor nor oppose requiring employers to offer paid leave to parents of new children?",
    "positive_answer": "no paid parental leave,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Favor a great deal",
      "Favor a moderate amount",
      "Favor a little",
      "Neither favor nor oppose",
      "Oppose a little",
      "Oppose a moderate amount",
      "Oppose a great deal"
    ]
  },
  "V201408x": {
    "title": "PRE: SUMMARY: SERVICES TO SAME SEX COUPLES",
    "question": "Do you think business owners who provide wedding-related services should be allowed to refuse services to same-sex couples if same-sex marriage violates their religious beliefs, or do you think business owners should be required to provide services regardless of a couple’s sexual orientation?",
    "positive_answer": "business should provide services to same sex couples,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Feels very strongly should be allowed to refuse services",
      "Feels moderately strongly should be allowed to refuse",
      "Feels a little strongly should be allowed to refuse services",
      "Feels a little strongly should be required to provide services",
      "Feels moderately strongly should be required to provide",
      "Feels very strongly should be required to provide services"
    ]
  },
  "V201411x": {
    "title": "PRE: SUMMARY: TRANSGENDER POLICY",
    "question": "Should transgender people - that is, people who identify themselves as the sex or gender different from the one they were born as - have to use the bathrooms of the gender they were born as, or should they be allowed to use the bathrooms of their identified gender?",
    "positive_answer": "against trans bathroom bills,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Feels very strongly transgender people should use bathroom of birth gender",
      "Feels moderately strongly transgender people should use bathroom of birth gender",
      "Feels a little strongly transgender people should use bathroom of birth gender",
      "Feels a little strongly transgender people be allowed to use bathroom of identified gender",
      "Feels moderately strongly transgender people be allowed to use bathroom of identified gender",
      "Feels very strongly transgender people be allowed to use bathroom of identified gender"
    ]
  },
  "V201414x": {
    "title": "PRE: SUMMARY: FAVOR/OPPOSE LAWS PROTECT GAYS LESBIANS AGAINST JOB DISCRIMINATION",
    "question": "Do you favor or oppose laws to protect gays and lesbians against job discrimination?",
    "positive_answer": "oppose gay antidiscrimiation law,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Favor strongly",
      "Favor not strongly",
      "Oppose not strongly",
      "Oppose strongly"
    ]
  },
  "V201415": {
    "title": "PRE: SHOULD GAY AND LESBIAN COUPLES BE ALLOWED TO ADOPT",
    "question": "Do you think gay or lesbian couples should be legally permitted to adopt children?",
    "positive_answer": "gay people shouldnt be allowed to adopt children,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Yes",
      "No"
    ]
  },
  "V201416": {
    "title": "PRE: R POSITION ON GAY MARRIAGE",
    "question": "Should gay people be allowed to get married?",
    "positive_answer": "no gay marriage,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Gay and lesbian couples should be allowed to legally marry",
      "Gay and lesbian couples should be allowed to form civil unions but not legally marry ",
      "There should be no legal recognition of gay or lesbian couples’ relationship"
    ]
  },
  "V201417": {
    "title": "PRE: US GOVERNMENT POLICY TOWARD UNAUTHORIZED IMMIGRANTS",
    "question": "How should US treat undocumented immigrants?",
    "positive_answer": "allow undocumented immigrants to become citizens,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Make all unauthorized immigrants felons and send them back to their home country ",
      "Have a guest worker program that allows unauthorized immigrants to remain in US to work but only for limited time ",
      "Allow unauthorized immigrants to remain in US & eventually qualify for citizenship but only if they meet requirements ",
      "Allow unauthorized immigrants to remain in US & eventually qualify for citizenship without penalties"
    ]
  },
  "V201420x": {
    "title": "PRE: SUMMARY: FAVOR OR OPPOSE ENDING BIRTHRIGHT CITIZENSHIP",
    "question": "Some people have proposed that the U.S. Constitution should be changed so that the children of unauthorized immigrants do not automatically get citizenship if they are born in this country. Do you favor, oppose, or neither favor nor oppose this proposal?",
    "positive_answer": "don't end birthright citizenship,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Favor a great deal",
      "Favor a moderate amount",
      "Favor a little",
      "Neither favor nor oppose",
      "Oppose a little",
      "Oppose a moderate amount",
      "Oppose a great deal"
    ]
  },
  "V201423x": {
    "title": "PRE: SUMMARY: SHOULD CHILDREN BROUGHT ILLEGALLY BE SENT BACK OR ALLOWED TO STAY",
    "question": "What should happen to immigrants who were brought to the U.S. illegally as children and have lived here for at least 10 years and graduated high school here? Should they be sent back where they came from, or should they be allowed to live and work in the United States?",
    "positive_answer": "children of undocumented shouldn't be deported,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Favors a great deal they should be sent back",
      "Favors a moderate amount they should be sent back",
      "Favors a little they should be sent back",
      "Favors a little they should be allowed to live and work in US",
      "Favors a moderate amount they should be allowed to live and work in US",
      "Favors a great deal they should be allowed to live and work in US"
    ]
  },
  "V201426x": {
    "title": "PRE: SUMMARY: FAVOR OR OPPOSE BUILDING A WALL ON BORDER WITH MEXICO",
    "question": "Do you favor, oppose, or neither favor nor oppose building a wall on the U.S. border with Mexico?",
    "positive_answer": "oppose border wall,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Favor a great deal",
      "Favor a moderate amount",
      "Favor a little",
      "Neither favor nor oppose",
      "Oppose a little",
      "Oppose a moderate amount",
      "Oppose a great deal"
    ]
  },
  "V201429": {
    "title": "PRE: BEST WAY TO DEAL WITH URBAN UNREST",
    "question": "What is the best way to deal with the problem of urban unrest and rioting?",
    "positive_answer": "use force to prevent urban unrest,",
    "all_answers": [
      "Solve problems of racism and police violence",
      "",
      "",
      "",
      "",
      "",
      "Use all available force to maintain law and order"
    ]
  },
  "V201626": {
    "title": "PRE: NEED TO BE MORE SENSITIVE TALKING OR PEOPLE TOO EASILY OFFENDED",
    "question": "Some people think that the way people talk needs to change with the times to be more sensitive to people from different backgrounds. Others think that this has already gone too far and many people are just too easily offended. Which is closer to your opinion?",
    "positive_answer": "people too easily offended",
    "all_answers": [
      "The way people talk needs to change a lot",
      "The way people talk needs to change a little",
      "People are a little too easily offended",
      "People are much too easily offended"
    ]
  },
  "V201639": {
    "title": "PRE: WOMEN INTERPRET INNOCENT REMARKS AS SEXIST",
    "question": "Do many women interpret innocent remarks or acts as being sexist?",
    "positive_answer": "most women don't interpret innocent remarks or acts as being sexist.",
    "all_answers": [
      "Agree strongly",
      "Agree somewhat",
      "Neither agree nor disagree",
      "Disagree somewhat",
      "Disagree strongly"
    ]
  },
  "V201640": {
    "title": "PRE: WOMEN SEEK TO GAIN POWER BY GETTING CONTROL OVER MEN",
    "question": "do women want to gain power by controlling men",
    "positive_answer": "women do not seek to gain power by controlling men",
    "all_answers": [
      "Agree strongly",
      "Agree somewhat",
      "Neither agree nor disagree",
      "Disagree somewhat",
      "Disagree strongly"
    ]
  },
  "V202212": {
    "title": "POST: [STD] PUBLIC OFFICIALS DON’T CARE WHAT PEOPLE THINK",
    "question": "do public officials don’t care much what people like you think?",
    "positive_answer": "public officials care what i think",
    "all_answers": [
      "Agree strongly",
      "Agree somewhat",
      "Neither agree nor disagree",
      "Disagree somewhat",
      "Disagree strongly"
    ]
  },
  "V202213": {
    "title": "POST: [STD] HAVE NO SAY ABOUT WHAT GOVERMENT DOES",
    "question": "do people like you have say in what the government does?",
    "positive_answer": "i have no say in govt",
    "all_answers": [
      "Agree strongly",
      "Agree somewhat",
      "Neither agree nor disagree",
      "Disagree somewhat",
      "Disagree strongly"
    ]
  },
  "V202231x": {
    "title": "POST: SUMMARY: FAVOR/OPPOSE NEW LIMITS ON IMPORTS",
    "question": "Some people have suggested placing new limits on foreign imports in order to protect American jobs. Others say that such limits would raise consumer prices and hurt American exports. Do you favor or oppose placing new limits on imports?",
    "positive_answer": "no new limits on imports",
    "all_answers": [
      "Favor strongly",
      "Favor not strongly",
      "Oppose not strongly",
      "Oppose strongly"
    ]
  },
  "V202232": {
    "title": "POST: WHAT SHOULD IMMIGRATION LEVELS BE",
    "question": "Do you think the number of immigrants from foreign countries who are permitted to come to the United States to live should be increased a lot, increased a little, left the same as it is now, decreased a little, or decreased a lot?",
    "positive_answer": "less immigrants",
    "all_answers": [
      "Increased a lot",
      "Increased a little",
      "Left the same as it is now",
      "Decreased a little",
      "Decreased a lot"
    ]
  },
  "V202236x": {
    "title": "POST: SUMMARY: FAVOR/OPPOSE ALLOWING REFUGEES TO COME TO US",
    "question": "Do you favor, oppose, or neither favor nor oppose allowing refugees who are fleeing war, persecution, or natural disasters in other countries to come to live in the U.S.?",
    "positive_answer": "oppose refugees",
    "all_answers": [
      "Favor a great deal",
      "Favor a moderate amount",
      "Favor a little",
      "Neither favor nor oppose",
      "Oppose a little",
      "Oppose a moderate amount",
      "Oppose a great deal"
    ]
  },
  "V202242x": {
    "title": "POST: SUMMARY: FAVOR/OPPOSE PROVIDING PATH TO CITIZESHIP",
    "question": "Do you favor, oppose, or neither favor nor oppose providing a path to citizenship for unauthorized immigrants who obey the law, pay a fine, and pass security checks?",
    "positive_answer": "no path to citizenship for undocumented",
    "all_answers": [
      "Favor a great deal",
      "Favor a moderate amount",
      "Favor a little",
      "Neither favor nor oppose",
      "Oppose a little",
      "Oppose a moderate amount",
      "Oppose a great deal"
    ]
  },
  "V202245x": {
    "title": "POST: SUMMARY: FAVOR/OPPOSE RETURNING UNAUTHORIZE IMMIGRANTS TO NATIVE COUNTRY",
    "question": "Do you favor, oppose, or neither favor nor oppose returning all unauthorized immigrants to their native countries?",
    "positive_answer": "oppose returning undocumented to birth countries",
    "all_answers": [
      "Favor a great deal",
      "Favor a moderate amount",
      "Favor a little",
      "Neither favor nor oppose",
      "Oppose a little",
      "Oppose a moderate amount",
      "Oppose a great deal"
    ]
  },
  "V202248x": {
    "title": "POST: SUMMARY: FAVOR/OPPOSE SEPARATING CHILDREN OF DETAINED IMMIGRANTS",
    "question": "Do you favor, oppose, or neither favor nor oppose separating the children of detained immigrants, rather than keeping them with their parents in adult detention centers?",
    "positive_answer": "dont separate undocumented kids from families",
    "all_answers": [
      "Favor a great deal",
      "Favor a moderate amount",
      "Favor a little",
      "Neither favor nor oppose",
      "Oppose a little",
      "Oppose a moderate amount",
      "Oppose a great deal"
    ]
  },
  "V202252x": {
    "title": "POST: SUMMARY: FAVOR/OPPOSE PREFERENTIAL HIRING/PROMOTION OF BLACKS",
    "question": "are you for or against preferential hiring and promotion of blacks?",
    "positive_answer": "no preferential hiring/promotion of blacks",
    "all_answers": [
      "Favor a great deal",
      "Favor a moderate amount",
      "Favor a little",
      "Neither favor nor oppose",
      "Oppose a little",
      "Oppose a moderate amount",
      "Oppose a great deal"
    ]
  },
  "V202255x": {
    "title": "POST: SUMMARY: LESS OR MORE GOVERNMENT",
    "question": "less government better or more that govt needs to do",
    "positive_answer": "more govt better",
    "all_answers": [
      "Feels strongly less government better",
      "Feels somewhat strongly less government better",
      "Feels not strongly less government better",
      "Feels not strongly more things government should be doing",
      "Feels somewhat stongly more things government should be doing",
      "Feels strongly more things government should be doing"
    ]
  },
  "V202259x": {
    "title": "POST: SUMMARY: FAVOR/OPPOSE GOVERNMENT TRYING TO REDUCE INCOME INEQUALITY",
    "question": "Next, do you favor, oppose, or neither favor nor oppose the government trying to reduce the difference in incomes between the richest and poorest households?",
    "positive_answer": "govt shouldnt reduce income inequality",
    "all_answers": [
      "Favor a great deal",
      "Favor a moderate amount",
      "Favor a little",
      "Neither favor nor oppose",
      "Oppose a little",
      "Oppose a moderate amount",
      "Oppose a great deal"
    ]
  },
  "V202260": {
    "title": "POST: SOCIETY SHOULD MAKE SURE EVERYONE HAS EQUAL OPPORTUNITY",
    "question": "Should our society do whatever is necessary to make sure that everyone has an equal opportunity to succeed?",
    "positive_answer": "shouldnt make sure everyone has equal opportunity",
    "all_answers": [
      "Agree strongly",
      "Agree somewhat",
      "Neither agree nor disagree",
      "Disagree somewhat",
      "Disagree strongly"
    ]
  },
  "V202261": {
    "title": "POST: WE’D BE BETTER OFF IF WORRIED LESS ABOUT EQUALITY",
    "question": "should we be more worried about equality?",
    "positive_answer": "should worry more about equality",
    "all_answers": [
      "Agree strongly",
      "Agree somewhat",
      "Neither agree nor disagree",
      "Disagree somewhat",
      "Disagree strongly"
    ]
  },
  "V202262": {
    "title": "POST: NOT A BIG PROBLEM IF SOME HAVE MORE CHANCE IN LIFE",
    "question": "Is it a problem if some have more chances in life?",
    "positive_answer": "problem if some have more chance in life",
    "all_answers": [
      "Agree strongly",
      "Agree somewhat",
      "Neither agree nor disagree",
      "Disagree somewhat",
      "Disagree strongly"
    ]
  },
  "V202263": {
    "title": "POST: IF PEOPLE WERE TREATED MORE FAIRLY WE WOULD HAVE FEWER PROBLEMS",
    "question": "Would we have fewer problems if people were treated more fairly?",
    "positive_answer": "wouldnt have fewer problems if people treated more equally",
    "all_answers": [
      "Agree strongly",
      "Agree somewhat",
      "Neither agree nor disagree",
      "Disagree somewhat",
      "Disagree strongly"
    ]
  },
  "V202264": {
    "title": "POST: THE WORLD IS CHANGING & WE SHOULD ADJUST VIEW OF MORAL BEHAVIOR",
    "question": "Should we change our views of moral behavior to fit the changing world?",
    "positive_answer": "shouldn't adjust morality to changing world",
    "all_answers": [
      "Agree strongly",
      "Agree somewhat",
      "Neither agree nor disagree",
      "Disagree somewhat",
      "Disagree strongly"
    ]
  },
  "V202265": {
    "title": "POST: FEWER PROBLEMS IF THERE WAS MORE EMPHASIS ON TRADITIONAL FAMILY VALUES",
    "question": "Would we have fewer problems if more focus on traditional family ties",
    "positive_answer": "wouldnt have less problems if focused more on traditional family ties",
    "all_answers": [
      "Agree strongly",
      "Agree somewhat",
      "Neither agree nor disagree",
      "Disagree somewhat",
      "Disagree strongly"
    ]
  },
  "V202270": {
    "title": "POST: BETTER IF REST OF WORLD MORE LIKE AMERICA",
    "question": "Would the world be better if people from other countries were more like Americans?",
    "positive_answer": "wouldnt be better if others more like americans",
    "all_answers": [
      "Agree strongly",
      "Agree somewhat",
      "Neither agree nor disagree",
      "Disagree somewhat",
      "Disagree strongly"
    ]
  },
  "V202273x": {
    "title": "POST: SUMMARY: US BETTER OR WORSE THAN MOST OTHER COUNTRIES",
    "question": "Is the US better or worse than other countries",
    "positive_answer": "US worse than other countries",
    "all_answers": [
      "Better",
      "Worse",
      "The same"
    ]
  },
  "V202279x": {
    "title": "POST: SUMMARY: PEOPLE IN RURAL AREAS HAVE TOO MUCH/TOO LITTLE INFLUENCE",
    "question": "Compared to people living in cities, do people living in small towns and rural areas have too much influence, too little influence, or about the right amount of influence on government?",
    "positive_answer": "rural people have too little govt influence",
    "all_answers": [
      "Much too much",
      "Somewhat too much",
      "A little too much",
      "About the right amount",
      "A little too little",
      "Somewhat too little",
      "Much too little"
    ]
  },
  "V202282x": {
    "title": "POST: SUMMARY: PEOPLE IN RURAL AREAS GET TOO MUCH/TOO LITTLE RESPECT",
    "question": "Do people living in small towns and rural areas get too much respect, too little respect, or about the right amount of respect from people living in cities?",
    "positive_answer": "rural people get too little respect",
    "all_answers": [
      "Much too much",
      "Somewhat too much",
      "A little too much",
      "About the right amount",
      "A little too little",
      "Somewhat too little",
      "Much too little"
    ]
  },
  "V202290x": {
    "title": "POST: SUMMARY: BETTER/WORSE IF MAN WORKS AND WOMAN TAKES CARE OF HOME",
    "question": "Is it better or worse if men work and women take care of the home",
    "positive_answer": "worse if traditional gender roles",
    "all_answers": [
      "Much better",
      "Somewhat better",
      "Slightly better",
      "Makes no difference",
      "Slightly worse",
      "Somewhat worse",
      "Much worse"
    ]
  },
  "V202291": {
    "title": "POST: DO WOMEN DEMANDING EQUALITY SEEK SPECIAL FAVORS",
    "question": "When women demand equality these days, how often are they actually seeking special favors?",
    "positive_answer": "women asking for equality dont want special favors",
    "all_answers": [
      "Always",
      "Most of the time",
      "About half the time",
      "Some of the time",
      "Never"
    ]
  },
  "V202292": {
    "title": "POST: DO WOMEN COMPLAINING ABOUT DISCRIMINATION CAUSE MORE PROBLEMS",
    "question": "When women complain about discrimination, how often do they cause more problems than they solve?",
    "positive_answer": "women complaining about discrimination dont cause more problems",
    "all_answers": [
      "Always",
      "Most of the time",
      "About half the time",
      "Some of the time",
      "Never"
    ]
  },
  "V202300": {
    "title": "POST: AGREE/DISAGREE: BLACKS SHOULD WORK THEIR WAY UP WITHOUT SPECIAL FAVORS",
    "question": "should blacks work their way up without special favors",
    "positive_answer": "disagree w 'blacks should work their way up without special favors'",
    "all_answers": [
      "Agree strongly",
      "Agree somewhat",
      "Neither agree nor disagree",
      "Disagree somewhat",
      "Disagree strongly"
    ]
  },
  "V202302": {
    "title": "POST: AGREE/DISAGREE: BLACKS HAVE GOTTEN LESS THAN THEY DESERVE",
    "question": "Over the past few years, blacks have gotten less than they deserve",
    "positive_answer": "blacks havent gotten less than they deserve",
    "all_answers": [
      "Agree strongly",
      "Agree somewhat",
      "Neither agree nor disagree",
      "Disagree somewhat",
      "Disagree strongly"
    ]
  },
  "V202303": {
    "title": "POST: AGREE/DISAGREE: IF BLACKS TRIED HARDER THEY’D BE AS WELL OFF AS WHITES",
    "question": "Would blacks be as well off as whites if they worked hard enough",
    "positive_answer": "blacks dont suffer prejudice because of lack of hard work",
    "all_answers": [
      "Agree strongly",
      "Agree somewhat",
      "Neither agree nor disagree",
      "Disagree somewhat",
      "Disagree strongly"
    ]
  },
  "V202304": {
    "title": "POST: OUR POLITICAL SYSTEM ONLY WORKS FOR INSIDERS WITH MONEY AND POWER",
    "question": "Does the political system only work for insiders with money and power?",
    "positive_answer": "politics only works for powerful",
    "all_answers": [
      "Not at all well",
      "Not very well",
      "Somewhat well",
      "Very well",
      "Extremely well"
    ]
  },
  "V202305": {
    "title": "POST: BECAUSE OF RICH AND POWERFUL IT’S DIFFICULT FOR THE REST TO GET AHEAD",
    "question": "Do rich and powerful make it harder for everyone else to get ahead?",
    "positive_answer": "powerful make it harder for others to get ahead",
    "all_answers": [
      "Not at all well",
      "Not very well",
      "Somewhat well",
      "Very well",
      "Extremely well"
    ]
  },
  "V202308x": {
    "title": "POST: SUMMARY: TRUST ORDINARY PEOPLE/EXPERTS FOR PUBLIC POLICY",
    "question": "When it comes to public policy decisions, whom do you tend to trust more: ordinary people, experts, or trust both the same?",
    "positive_answer": "trust experts more than ordinary people",
    "all_answers": [
      "Trust ordinary people much more",
      "Trust ordinary people somewhat more",
      "Trust both the same",
      "Trust experts somwhat more",
      "Trust experts much more"
    ]
  },
  "V202309": {
    "title": "POST: HOW MUCH DO PEOPLE NEED HELP FROM EXPERTS TO UNDERSTAND SCIENCE",
    "question": "How much do ordinary people need the help of experts to understand complicated things like science and health?",
    "positive_answer": "people need help from experts to understand science",
    "all_answers": [
      "Not at all",
      "A little",
      "A moderate amount",
      "A lot",
      "A great deal"
    ]
  },
  "V202310": {
    "title": "POST: HOW IMPORTANT SHOULD SCIENCE BE FOR DECISIONS ABOUT COVID-19",
    "question": "In general, how important should science be for making government decisions about COVID-19?",
    "positive_answer": "science important for covid decisions",
    "all_answers": [
      "Not at all important",
      "A little important",
      "Moderately important",
      "Very important",
      "Extremely important"
    ]
  },
  "V202311": {
    "title": "POST: BUSINESS AND POLITICS CONTROLLED BY FEW POWERFUL PEOPLE",
    "question": "How well does the following statement describe your view? “Most business and politics in this country are secretly controlled by the same few powerful people.”",
    "positive_answer": "business/politics controlled by powerful few",
    "all_answers": [
      "Not at all",
      "Not very well",
      "Somewhat well",
      "Very well",
      "Extremely well"
    ]
  },
  "V202312": {
    "title": "POST: MUCH OF WHAT PEOPLE HEAR IN SCHOOLS AND MEDIA ARE LIES BY THOSE IN POWER",
    "question": "Is much of the info in school and media lies designed to benefit powerful?",
    "positive_answer": "schools/media lie to benefit powerful few",
    "all_answers": [
      "Not at all",
      "Not very well",
      "Somewhat well",
      "Very well",
      "Extremely well"
    ]
  },
  "V202317": {
    "title": "POST: HOW MUCH OPPORTUNITY IN AMERICA FOR AVERAGE PERSON TO GET AHEAD",
    "question": "How much opportunity is there in America today for the average person to get ahead?",
    "positive_answer": "no opportunity for average person to get ahead",
    "all_answers": [
      "A great deal",
      "A lot",
      "A moderate amount",
      "A little",
      "None"
    ]
  },
  "V202321": {
    "title": "POST: IMPORTANCE OF REDUCING DEFICIT",
    "question": "How important is it to reduce the deficit?",
    "positive_answer": "reducing defecit not important",
    "all_answers": [
      "Extremely important",
      "Very important",
      "Moderately important",
      "A little important",
      "Not at all important"
    ]
  },
  "V202328x": {
    "title": "POST: SUMMARY: APPROVE/DISAPPROVE AFFORDABLE CARE ACT",
    "question": "Do you approve, disapprove, or neither approve nor disapprove of the Affordable Care Act of 2010, sometimes called Obamacare?",
    "positive_answer": "disapprove obamacare",
    "all_answers": [
      "Approve a great deal",
      "Approve a moderate amount",
      "Approve a little",
      "Neither approve nor disapprove",
      "Disapprove a little",
      "Disapprove a moderate amount",
      "Disapprove a great deal"
    ]
  },
  "V202331x": {
    "title": "POST: SUMMARY: FAVOR/OPPOSE REQUIRING VACCINES IN SCHOOLS",
    "question": "Do you favor, oppose, or neither favor nor oppose requiring children to be vaccinated in order to attend public schools?",
    "positive_answer": "disapprove vaccines",
    "all_answers": [
      "Favor a great deal",
      "Favor a moderate amount",
      "Favor a little",
      "Neither favor nor oppose",
      "Oppose a little",
      "Oppose a moderate amount",
      "Oppose a great deal"
    ]
  },
  "V202336x": {
    "title": "POST: SUMMARY: FAVOR/OPPOSE INCREASED REGULATION ON GREENHOUSE EMISSIONS",
    "question": "Do you favor, oppose, or neither favor nor oppose increased government regulation on businesses that produce a great deal of greenhouse emissions linked to climate change?",
    "positive_answer": "oppose climate change regulation",
    "all_answers": [
      "Favor a great deal",
      "Favor a moderate amount",
      "Favor a little",
      "Neither favor nor oppose",
      "Oppose a little",
      "Oppose a moderate amount",
      "Oppose a great deal"
    ]
  },
  "V202341x": {
    "title": "POST: SUMMARY: FAVOR/OPPOSE BACKGROUND CHECKS FOR GUN PUCHASES",
    "question": "Do you favor, oppose, or neither favor nor oppose requiring background checks for gun purchases at gun shows or other private sales?",
    "positive_answer": "oppose gun purchase background checks",
    "all_answers": [
      "Favor a great deal",
      "Favor a moderate amount",
      "Favor a little",
      "Neither favor nor oppose",
      "Oppose a little",
      "Oppose a moderate amount",
      "Oppose a great deal"
    ]
  },
  "V202344x": {
    "title": "POST: SUMMARY: FAVOR/OPPOSE BANNING ‘ASSAULT-STYLE’ RIFLES",
    "question": "Do you favor, oppose, or neither favor nor oppose banning the sale of semi-automatic “assault-style” rifles?",
    "positive_answer": "oppose assault weapons ban",
    "all_answers": [
      "Favor a great deal",
      "Favor a moderate amount",
      "Favor a little",
      "Neither favor nor oppose",
      "Oppose a little",
      "Oppose a moderate amount",
      "Oppose a great deal"
    ]
  },
  "V202347x": {
    "title": "POST: FAVOR/OPPOSE GOVERNMENT BUY BACK OF ‘ASSAULT-STYLE’ RIFLES",
    "question": "Do you favor, oppose, or neither favor nor oppose a mandatory program where the government would buy back semi-automatic assault-style rifles from citizens who currently own them?",
    "positive_answer": "oppose assault weapon buyback",
    "all_answers": [
      "Favor a great deal",
      "Favor a moderate amount",
      "Favor a little",
      "Neither favor nor oppose",
      "Oppose a little",
      "Oppose a moderate amount",
      "Oppose a great deal"
    ]
  },
  "V202350x": {
    "title": "POST: SUMMARY SHOULD FEDERAL GOVT DO MORE/LESS ABOUT OPIOID DRUG ADDICTION",
    "question": "Do you think the federal government should be doing more about the opioid drug addiction issue, should be doing less, or is it currently doing the right amount?",
    "positive_answer": "govt should do less abt opioid crisis",
    "all_answers": [
      "Should be doing a great deal more",
      "Should be doing a moderate amount more",
      "Should be doing a little more",
      "Is doing the right amount",
      "Should be doing a little less",
      "Should be doing a moderate amount less",
      "Should be doing a lot less"
    ]
  },
  "V202351": {
    "title": "POST: HOW OFTEN DO POLICE OFFICERS USE MORE FORCE THAN NECESSARY",
    "question": "How often do you think police officers use more force than is necessary?",
    "positive_answer": "police overuse force",
    "all_answers": [
      "Never",
      "Rarely",
      "About half the time",
      "Most of the time",
      "All the time"
    ]
  },
  "V202364x": {
    "title": "POST: SUMMARY: INCREASING TRADE GOOD/BAD FOR INTERNATIONAL RELATIONSHIPS",
    "question": "Is increasing the amount of international trade good, bad, or neither good nor bad for our relationships with other countries?",
    "positive_answer": "int trade increase bad",
    "all_answers": [
      "Very good",
      "Somewhat good",
      "Neither good nor bad",
      "Somewhat bad",
      "Very bad"
    ]
  },
  "V202373x": {
    "title": "POST: SUMMARY: INCREASING DIVERSITY MADE US BETTER/WORSE PLACE TO LIVE",
    "question": "Does the increasing number of people of many different races and ethnic groups in the United States make this country a better place to live, a worse place to live, or does it make no difference?",
    "positive_answer": "diversity makes US worse",
    "all_answers": [
      "A lot better",
      "A little better",
      "Makes no difference",
      "A little worse",
      "A lot worse"
    ]
  },
  "V202376x": {
    "title": "POST: SUMMARY: FAVOR/OPPOSE FEDERAL PROGRAM GIVING CITIZENS $12K/YEAR",
    "question": "Do you favor, oppose, or neither favor nor oppose establishing a federal program that gives all citizens $12,000 per year, provided they meet certain conditions? This program would be paid for with higher taxes.",
    "positive_answer": "against $12k/year ubi",
    "all_answers": [
      "Favor a great deal",
      "Favor a moderate amount",
      "Favor a little",
      "Neither favor nor oppose",
      "Oppose a little",
      "Oppose a moderate amount",
      "Oppose a great deal"
    ]
  },
  "V202377": {
    "title": "POST: SHOULD THE MINIMUM WAGE BE RAISED, KEPT THE SAME, OR LOWERED",
    "question": "Should the federal minimum wage be raised, kept the same, lowered but not eliminated, or eliminated altogether?",
    "positive_answer": "decrease minimum wage",
    "all_answers": [
      "Raised",
      "Kept the same",
      "Lowered",
      "Eliminated"
    ]
  },
  "V202380x": {
    "title": "POST: SUMMARY: INCREASE/DECREASE GOVERNMENT SPENDING TO HELP PAY FOR HEALTH CARE",
    "question": "Do you favor an increase, decrease, or no change in government spending to help people pay for health insurance when they can’t pay for it all themselves?",
    "positive_answer": "decrease govt healthcare spending",
    "all_answers": [
      "Increase a great deal",
      "Increase a moderate amount",
      "Increase a little",
      "No change",
      "Decrease a little",
      "Decrease a moderate amount",
      "Decrease a great deal"
    ]
  },
  "V202387x": {
    "title": "POST: SUMMARY: ATTENTION TO SEXUAL HARRASSMENT AS GONE TOO FAR/NOT FAR ENOUGH",
    "question": "Do you think attention to sexual harassment has gone too far, has not gone far enough, or has been about right?",
    "positive_answer": "too little attn. to sexual harassement",
    "all_answers": [
      "Has gone much too far",
      "Has gone a little too far",
      "Has been about right",
      "Has not gone quite far enough",
      "Has not gone nearly far enough"
    ]
  },
  "V202390x": {
    "title": "POST: SUMMARY: FAVOR/OPPOSE TRANSENDER PEOPLE SERVE IN MILITARY",
    "question": "Do you favor, oppose, or neither favor nor oppose allowing transgender people to serve in the United States Armed Forces?",
    "positive_answer": "against trans military service",
    "all_answers": [
      "Favor a great deal",
      "Favor a moderate amount",
      "Favor a little",
      "Neither favor nor oppose",
      "Oppose a little",
      "Oppose a moderate amount",
      "Oppose a great deal"
    ]
  },
  "V202400": {
    "title": "POST: HOW MUCH IS CHINA A THREAT TO THE UNITED STATES",
    "question": "How much is China a threat to the United States?",
    "positive_answer": "China threat to US",
    "all_answers": []
  },
  "V202401": {
    "title": "POST: HOW MUCH IS RUSSIA A THREAT TO THE UNITED STATES",
    "question": "How much is Russia a threat to the United States?",
    "positive_answer": "Russia threat to US",
    "all_answers": []
  },
  "V202402": {
    "title": "POST: HOW MUCH IS MEXICO A THREAT TO THE UNITED STATES",
    "question": "How much is Mexico a threat to the United States?",
    "positive_answer": "Mexico threat to US",
    "all_answers": []
  },
  "V202403": {
    "title": "POST: HOW MUCH IS IRAN A THREAT TO THE UNITED STATES",
    "question": "How much is Iran a threat to the United States?",
    "positive_answer": "Iran threat to US",
    "all_answers": []
  },
  "V202404": {
    "title": "POST: HOW MUCH IS JAPAN A THREAT TO THE UNITED STATES",
    "question": "How much is Japan a threat to the United States?",
    "positive_answer": "Japan threat to US",
    "all_answers": []
  },
  "V202405": {
    "title": "POST: HOW MUCH IS GERMANY A THREAT TO THE UNITED STATES",
    "question": "How much is Germany a threat to the United States?",
    "positive_answer": "Germany threat to US",
    "all_answers": []
  },
  "V202409": {
    "title": "POST: CSES5-Q04A: ATTITUDES ABOUT ELITES: COMPROMISE IN POLITICS IS SELLING OUT",
    "question": "Do you agree with the following statement: 'What people call compromise in politics is really just selling out on one’s principles.' ",
    "positive_answer": "compromise in politics not selling out on principles.",
    "all_answers": [
      "Agree strongly",
      "Agree somewhat",
      "Neither agree nor disagree",
      "Disagree somewhat",
      "Disagree strongly"
    ]
  },
  "V202410": {
    "title": "POST: CSES5-Q04B: ATTITUDES ABOUT ELITES: POLITICIANS DO NOT CARE ABOUT PEOPLE",
    "question": "Do you agree with the following statement: 'Most politicians do not care about the people.' ",
    "positive_answer": "politicians care about people",
    "all_answers": [
      "Agree strongly",
      "Agree somewhat",
      "Neither agree nor disagree",
      "Disagree somewhat",
      "Disagree strongly"
    ]
  },
  "V202411": {
    "title": "POST: CSES5-Q04C: ATTITUDES ABOUT ELITES: MOST POLITICIANS ARE TRUSTWORTHY",
    "question": "Do you agree with the following statement: 'Most politicians are trustworthy.' ",
    "positive_answer": "politicians not trustworthy",
    "all_answers": [
      "Agree strongly",
      "Agree somewhat",
      "Neither agree nor disagree",
      "Disagree somewhat",
      "Disagree strongly"
    ]
  },
  "V202412": {
    "title": "POST: CSES5-Q04D: ATTITUDES ABOUT ELITES: POLITICIANS ARE MAIN PROBLEM IN US",
    "question": "Do you agree with the following statement: 'Politicians are the main problem in the United States.' ",
    "positive_answer": "politicians not main problem in US",
    "all_answers": [
      "Agree strongly",
      "Agree somewhat",
      "Neither agree nor disagree",
      "Disagree somewhat",
      "Disagree strongly"
    ]
  },
  "V202413": {
    "title": "POST: CSES5-Q04E: ATTITUDES ABOUT ELITES: STRONG LEADER IN GOVERNMENT IS GOOD",
    "question": "Do you agree with the following statement: 'Having a strong leader in government is good for the United States even if the leader bends the rules to get things done.' ",
    "positive_answer": "strong leader that bends rule bad for US",
    "all_answers": [
      "Agree strongly",
      "Agree somewhat",
      "Neither agree nor disagree",
      "Disagree somewhat",
      "Disagree strongly"
    ]
  },
  "V202414": {
    "title": "POST: CSES5-Q04F: ATTITUDES ABOUT ELITES: PEOPLE SHOULD MAKE POLICY DECISIONS",
    "question": "Do you agree with the following statement: 'The people, and not politicians, should make our most important policy decisions.' ",
    "positive_answer": "politicans should make policy instead of people",
    "all_answers": [
      "Agree strongly",
      "Agree somewhat",
      "Neither agree nor disagree",
      "Disagree somewhat",
      "Disagree strongly"
    ]
  },
  "V202415": {
    "title": "POST: CSES5-Q04G: ATTITUDES ABOUT ELITES: POLITICIANS ONLY CARE ABOUT THE RICH",
    "question": "Do you agree with the following statement: 'Most politicians care only about the interests of the rich and powerful.' ",
    "positive_answer": "politicians don't only care about rich/powerful",
    "all_answers": [
      "Agree strongly",
      "Agree somewhat",
      "Neither agree nor disagree",
      "Disagree somewhat",
      "Disagree strongly"
    ]
  },
  "V202416": {
    "title": "POST: CSES5-Q05A: OUT-GROUP ATTITUDES: MINORITIES SHOULD ADAPT",
    "question": "Do you agree with the following statement: 'Minorities should adapt to the customs and traditions of the United States.' ",
    "positive_answer": "minorities shouldn't adapt to customs of US",
    "all_answers": [
      "Agree strongly",
      "Agree somewhat",
      "Neither agree nor disagree",
      "Disagree somewhat",
      "Disagree strongly"
    ]
  },
  "V202417": {
    "title": "POST: CSES5-Q05B: OUT-GROUP ATTITUDES: WILL OF MAJORITY SHOULD ALWAYS PREVAIL",
    "question": "Do you agree with the following statement: 'The will of the majority should always prevail, even over the rights of minorities.' ",
    "positive_answer": "will of majority shouldn't prevail over minority rights'",
    "all_answers": [
      "Agree strongly",
      "Agree somewhat",
      "Neither agree nor disagree",
      "Disagree somewhat",
      "Disagree strongly"
    ]
  },
  "V202421": {
    "title": "POST: CSES5-Q06A: NATIONAL IDENTITY: HOW IMPORTANT TO HAVE BEEN BORN IN US",
    "question": "Some people say that the following things are important for being truly American. Others says they are not important. How important do you think the following is for being truly American: very important, fairly important, not very important, or not important at all? To have been born in the United States.",
    "positive_answer": "Not important to be born in us to be american",
    "all_answers": [
      "Very important",
      "Fairly important",
      "Not very important",
      "Not important at all"
    ]
  },
  "V202425": {
    "title": "POST: CSES5-Q07: HOW WIDESPREAD IS CORRUPTION AMONG POLITICIANS IN US",
    "question": "How widespread do you think corruption such as bribe taking is among politicians in the United States:",
    "positive_answer": "Polticial corruption hardly happens",
    "all_answers": [
      "Very widespread",
      "Quite widespread",
      "Not very widespread",
      "Hardly happens at all"
    ]
  },
  "V202426": {
    "title": "POST: CSES5-Q08: GOVERNMENT SHOULD REDUCE DIFFERENCES IN INCOME LEVELS",
    "question": "Please say to what extent you agree or disagree with the following statement: ‘The government should take measures to reduce differences in income levels’. Do you agree strongly, agree somewhat, neither agree or disagree, disagree somewhat, or disagree strongly?",
    "positive_answer": "govt shouldnt reduce diff in income",
    "all_answers": [
      "Agree strongly",
      "Agree somewhat",
      "Neither agree nor disagree",
      "Disagree somewhat",
      "Disagree strongly"
    ]
  }
}